Majority of students know the difference between rational and
irrational numbers. So
in today's video we will learn how
you can tell whether it is a rational number
or an irrational number just by looking at it. So a basic
definition of a rational number is that any
value which we can write in the format of p-value is
a rational number, that is,
I need a fraction or let's say
I need an exact value to call that number a
rational number. So now the doubt that
most of the students have is that
when a digit is repeating after the decimal,
like 0.06 6666 and it keeps going, then is it a
rational number or a rational
number. So friends, this number is a
number with bars, that is 0.666 66,
you can also call it 0.6 bar and the bar can be
solved in fraction, that is,
what is this also, we have a rational number.
Now your comment  One irrational number has to be mentioned in the section