this is math with Mr J let's take a look
at rational numbers now rational numbers
are numbers that can be written as a
fraction of two integers or if
something's in decimal form and it
either terminates or repeats it's
rational for example let's jump into
number one where we have five can we
write this as a fraction of two integers
yes for example 5 over 1 or
25 over 5 or
50 over 10 all of those are examples of
fractions of two integers that equal
five so five is a rational number for
number two we have 910s this is a
terminating decimal so right away we can
see that this is rational but let's
write it as a fraction of two integers
we can write this as 910th so 9 over 10
18 over 20 and so on 910s is a rational
number click here for a more detailed
explanation until next time peace